hey everybody how's it going Tom here
from Attack on cardboard and we are
playing in the early access event thanks
to Wizards of the Coast uh without
further Ado let's jump into some of the
decks we'll be playing tonight so first
up we have a fight rigging deck
looking to abuse this bad boy here Arch
fiend of the dross a four Mana six six
with flying
archfield dross enters the battlefield
with four oil counters on it
at the beginning of your upkeep remove
an oil counter from the arch fan of
dross then if it has no oils oil
counters on it you lose the game
and whenever a creature an opponent
control dies its controller loses to
life
so first of all
it's a four minor six six with flying
and while yes we'll lose the game if all
the oil counters are removed from it at
the beginning of our upkeep
but
if we hit someone with this
just three times
that's 18 damage
we're gonna kill them before we lose the
game
or they just you know remove this
creature
so
archfienda dross is an absolute boss and
of course this combo is very nicely with
fight rigging three minor enchantment
from new Kapena
has Hideaway five and at the beginning
of combat on your turn put a plus one
plus one count on target creature you
control then if you control a creature
with power 7 or greater you may play the
exiled card without paying its minor
cost
so putting a plus one plus one counter
on Arch fiend address turns it into a
7-7 meaning we immediately
get to play whatever we have hidden
under fight rigging
uh and of course to ramp into the arch
fiend of dross we've got
armored Scarab gorger a two minor zero
three that gets plus three plus o as
long as it has three or more oil
counters on it doesn't really come up
too much has tap add One Mono of any
color
and whatever armor skate gorger becomes
tapped Exile Target card from a
graveyard and put an oil counter on
Armored scrap gorger so not only is it a
Mana ramper it's also graveyard hate
which sometimes comes up
uh aside from that removal go through a
throat very good
uh we've got gwena eyes of Gaia uh two
three for three that says add two minor
of any combination of colors spend this
Mana only to cast creature spells or
activate abilities of creature cards
whenever you cast a creature spell with
five power or greater put a plus one
plus one counter on gwena and untap it
so once again
we've got the bad boys here archuina
drosco is great gwena you can play out
uh I think I've had one game where I
played out two arch fiends of dross on
turn
four
and then played a third one on on turn
five uh ridiculously good with multiple
Arch fiends uh next up we've got bloated
contaminator this guy is an absolute
Beast a three Mana four four
with trample toxic one and whenever it
deals combat damage to a player we get
to proliferate so not only do we get two
periphery the plus one plus one sorry
the toxic counters uh poison counters we
get to proliferate plus one plus one
counters that we get from fight rigging
in koena
we get to proliferate the oil counters
if somehow we
are not winning the game with this card
we get to put more oil counters on it uh
oh one other thing with archery end of
dross
um
unlike cars like the
vegetable dinosaur the toporary stomper
this thing can block so we can play it
on turn three or four and it can
immediately block unlike some of these
other larger cards that have drawbacks
of it being tapped
um yeah just really good card you'll see
you'll see how well uh moving up we've
got root wire amalgam uh we can just
play it as a two minor two three uh or
what we want to do is just Chuck it down
for five Mana uh which also triggers
gwena
and it's obviously got that activated
ability the way we can make it a 1515 or
of course if we put some fight rigging
counters on it it's gonna get pretty big
uh
tolvard's hunt Master just an excellent
car to ramp into not much needs to be
said about this card
we've got Nissa the newest most badass
Planeswalker so for seven Mana we get a
seven loyalty Planeswalker that can
instantly
I might need to move over here that can
instantly ultimate
um
so
let's call to go over these abilities so
plus one creating XX frexian horror
creature token where X is nissa's
loyalty so we have to put the Loyalty
counter on it and then
it becomes the XX and now I initially
thought this was a I got them confused I
initially thought the token would be
um
star star where it would constantly
check uh and this is loyalty no it's
similar to ren7 where the token comes
down it sees how much loyalty Nissa has
and that's its power and toughness it
doesn't change negative one destroy
tiger artifact or enchantment
really solid ability and -7 until end of
turn creatures you control get plus one
plus one for each Forest you control and
gain trample uh being able to give
archery into dross trample or the 1515
that we get from root wire amalgam
is really really good
um we're running only five forests plus
The Proving Grounds
um so usually when this is Ultima goes
off we're usually getting just classic
overrun stats so plus three plus three
um but the trample is the key here
uh outside of that just a typical land
base we're running one beside you one
takanuma Proving Grounds and missions
Factory just for a free easy beat stick
um so without further ado
let's jump into the game
alrighty game one
so we've got two lands the arch fiend
with gwena we're on the play
if we draw one more land
this hand is nuts
all right let's risk it for the content
we'll start off with the wastes
worst case we got root wire onto
and
all right root wire on two
are we playing against rats oh
better to be lucky than to be good
blind belly toxic one when blank belly
rat dies proliferate
damn
better to be lucky than good
so again the counters on here don't
matter because it's either gonna deal
the damage
or it's just gonna die
here we go
question is do we
gains haste
I think we we booed up the root wire
here do we
no we probably don't we probably save
Niche um our removal spell for Nishi
here
player land
just one more land and I told Vasa gonna
take over the game here
kuramonix ranking
otherwise you can have other apps you
can draw have toxic one when it enters
the battlefield of the top five cards
put a rat among them into your hand
uh okay
I think we're gonna have to kill
kuramonix here
and block the Nashi
wow wow top sex another harmonics
um
if he's just attacking manashi we are
just going to
destroy Nashi
guys what did I say
better to be lucky than to be good
and I don't know how the rap deck is
going to deal with this
thank you
rats rats
rat is not going to do it I'm afraid
let's get in with the crew
there we go game one
alrighty here we go going into game two
here and unlike the last hand this is a
snap key we've got our three lands we've
got our fight rigging
we've got our bloated contaminators
let's do this
font of progress enters the battlefield
oh up against mildag
we'll hang on to beside you here
this looks like a very interesting
deck
we're gonna play the technoma here just
because
we may need the passage you
now there is the bounce spell that
proliferates yeah serum snare
Here Comes Jace
I know
so
I'm gonna play play Proving Grounds
the question is do we want to go Guana
I think we still go bloated contaminator
that's fine we're gonna drop our fight
rigging here
we are going to hide I think we're just
gonna hide another fight we're getting
underneath it to be honest
and I think we killed Jace or at least
try to
foreign
I think we can play the beside you here
put down arm scrap gorger
mind splice apparatus flash at the
beginning upkeep instance Source
response costs one less for ease each
counter
the race is on
we have got another contaminator I don't
know if we're exiling anything here
let's just get our beat sticks on the
board
we're gonna get rid of Jace get an oil
counter
playing land
ah we could have put it on
and it doesn't really matter
consuming Tides return choose an online
permanent control return all
non-permanents this way to the owner's
hand in drawer card for each
so what do we keep out here
yeah we have to keep the bloated
contaminator because he gets the
enchantment back either way
we are going to kill this thing now
plant contaminator
and we're gonna hang on to The Proving
Grounds
as we might need some card draw
so this is this artifact is is great
as long as as long as our opponent has
got some uh
card drawer to go with it which doesn't
look like they do
Nissa here would be nice oh yes
let's take a Nessa
play Guana
damn
so once again
we need some control
otherwise not really doing much
that is a big boy all right let's play
the root wire amalgam
all right we're getting our Nissa
next term
36 cards we are fine
and straight to that combat step
one Nissa please
and
I think we're just gonna get rid of
I feel like the font card
he's going to draw into an extra spell
and it's just going to destroy us
playing a land and the turn
it's fine
now that we've got the Nissa on the
field
really run away with the game here
to record
nice
all right let's go down another fight
rigging
I'm going to root wire amalgam
then if you control a creature okay
we do control a creature with seven
we get the five version thank you
get rid of that consuming side
damn I think we got it
okay
I'm keeping this around
foreign
we'll get the
tolva
fight rigging
we'll get the fight rigging
thank you
we'll get the arch fiend
cast The Hunt master
I think we got there
multiples
now if any of our creatures die
we
we get the old
dress triggers
all right
I think we might kill them here
woof
on to the next one alrighty here we go
game number three
and
if we draw another Arch fiend
gwena is going to be amazing here
going to I mean even if we don't
just Gwenna into Arch fiend into fight
rigging and we maybe cast the Nissa
off of fight rigging
Defector might this card is really good
um
yeah death camp
so this is Mom but with frexian Mana and
toxic
should be fine here if as long as Gwenna
doesn't die
we're actually in really good shape and
if we draw an untapped land we get to
play two arch fiends next turn
all right there's a another going up
so
I think we still do play both Arch
fiends
okay
Arch fiend
you got more removal
I mean now we can't block
because of Defector might
yep I can't block
toxic two so I think we are going to
lose the game
um so it's got four attacks
so with root wire we can potentially
block one here
even then that's not going to do it
need to be able to kill two of them
Nissa doesn't do it
I mean I guess we'll see
he's got removal
that's just it
okay mondrak
okay yeah you can you can choose black
but my colorless creature can block it
not a green creature my dude
oh
so
so I think we need to
fight rigging
let's see what we get
oh my word Tovar here is
amazing
so tolva
I think we still played the root wire
foreign
do we attack the arch fiend
I think we do
this sets up lethal for next term
did we just get there
he's got removal for my
root wire
oh my word
yeah we lose
damn that was a close game
so
if we held back we might have been able
to win that
but
tough game all right one more
and
not too bad of a hand
got a two drop with the root wire if you
need to
a piece of removal Arch fiend tolvar
if we draw any of our mono ramp here
this will be good
evolving adaptive oh my word we drew
some ramp
gets bigger when stuff that is bigger
than it comes into play
so angry deck uh so we'll keep up go for
the throat here
so this guy do he gets plus one plus
oath each oil counter
when it answers Battlefield put into the
graveyard
we just play our root wire here
I think we do root wire at the very
least blocks everything
oh these aren't plus one plus one
counters these are oil counters
churning Reservoir
so it's playing adaptive oil deck
it's fine you can take the hits
gwena
we've actually got the gwena combo here
going to into Arch fiend into Arch fiend
yeah so
probably not blocking here
and you're about to witness the power of
gwena and Arch fiend here
so
Arch Fiend The First
I'm gonna have to play this
Arch fiends the second
you'll go
this is a really nice combo
involving adaptive
churning Reservoir
this Dominus is non-combat damage
nothing has reach so I mean that
looks like they just might die
green green hunt master
foreign
not missing anything right nothing deals
non-combat damage
to cast the root wire probably not
[Music]
goodness this doesn't have
um
trample
deals double that and that's non-combat
damage so playing Green for the fight
spells
I'm getting in with the team
so
yeah that's
not block the Dominus
is everything blocked
and there we go
oh
it's basically a four minor Massacre
worm
so there we go
fight rigging doc deck there is
definitely some potential here with
archfiend of Dross
do not sleep in this card
either it kills your opponent
or they kill it so it's drawback
literally doesn't matter
Nissa performing as well as as you know
everybody thought absolutely fantastic
card provides blocker destroys important
uh permanence and can win you the game
with the ultimate
Guana goes awesomely with Arch fiend
archery and goes awesome with fight
rigging
bloated contaminator well we didn't play
it in too many games it's still a
ridiculous threat
I think I'm crafting this deck day one
this this looks really nice
but yeah let me know what you think in
the comments down below stay tuned for
more or will be one content thanks for
watching and I'll see you guys next time